I know you’re worried about Tosaki-san,
but please try to stay calm.
I won’t let you escape!
However you think about it,
picking a fight with America isn’t rational.
They’ve taken the road we expected.
Oh no!
I really hate women like you.
You picked this fight.
Kuro-chan, just once more,
please!
It really would have been best
to keep you locked up for experiments!
You should learn when
to shut your mouth!
Make no mistake.
I’m just
starting a new life.
The minister-
What about the minister’s schedule?
You mean-
Was it today?!
What were you thinking?
All our plans have gone to waste!
Ha, playing dead
is pretty fun.
Your demands were
the recognition of rights for Ajin, correct?
I can help you!
Satou-san.
He said they’d recognize our demands...!
Politicians.
Lying is their job.
The only lead we had was the minister.
Now he’s dead.
There’s nothing more to be done.
It seems like
there’s still hope.
We have one target remaining.
President Hashiguchi of Musashi Heavy Industries.
At the Board of Directors meeting
in three days, at 7 p.m.,
I’m going to kill him.
He’s giving a date and time for the attack?
Satou-san might like to fight,
but what he really likes is playing games.
This is a declaration of war.
No matter how he tries to hide,
we'll find him and kill him.
♪目を醒せ　このdistiny♪
Me o samase seou destiny, nogarerarenai no nara
Open your eyes Take on destiny If you can’t escape
♪逃れられないのなら♪
♪正しさも過ちも
全てを飲み込み闘う♪
Munashisa mo ayamachi mo, Subete o nomikomi tatakau
The futility and mistakes take them all in and fight
♪騒(ざわ)めく　心の闇を
司(つかさど)る脅威♪
Zawameku kokoro no yami o tsukasadoru kyoui
Menace rules the darkness of the murmuring heart
♪理性を　失くしかけてる
人間の真理♪
Risei o nakushikaketeru, ningen no shinri
Human psychology almost losing rationality
♪僕は知る　その無意味さを♪
Boku wa shiru  Sono muimisa o
I know how meaningless it is
♪偽りの平穏さえ　砕け散るなら♪
Itsuwari no heion sae kudakechiru darou
If only the tranquility of lies is smashed up
♪抗(あらが)う影　落とす♪
Aragau kage o toosu
Fight through the opposing shadow
♪It's the end of escape
立ち上がる♪
The end of escape, tachiagaru, sono michi shika nai kara
The end of escape, Make a stand, That’s the only way
♪その道しかないから♪
♪辿り着け　僕が目指した
小さなその希望に♪
Tadoritsuke boku ga mezashita chiisana sono kibou ni
Struggle towards that tiny hope I aimed for
♪差し伸べた　その手から♪
Sashinobeta sono te kara, koboreochita yowasa wa
The weakness spilling over from that outstretched hand
♪零れ落ちた弱さは♪
Orokashisa mo ayamachi mo subete o nomikomi kurutta
The foolishness and mistakes, I’ve gone mad taking them all in
♪正しさも過ちも
全てを飲み込み狂った♪
Things are getting kind of
tough in this country.
（報道陣たちのけん騒）
（報道陣１）
取締役会は開くんですね！
So you’re holding the board of director’s meeting?
Isn’t that pretty reckless?
（報道陣２）
あまりに無謀ではありませんか！
（報道陣３）
具体的な警備体制は！
What are your plans for security?
Will you be okay?
（橋口(はしぐち)）
私は何があっても
テロリストには屈しません
No matter what happens,
I refuse to give in to terrorists.
I am Chief Cabinet Secretary Mitsui.
（三井(みつい)）
官房長官の三井です
In response to continued acts of terrorism,
度重なるテロ行為に対し―
the Cabinet has met and decided as
a result to enact a new law.
政府内で閣議決定された
亜人に対する特別措置法が―
本会議で成立しました
（テレビ音声:三井）
そして今回の法案により―
Under these new measures,
新たな防衛部隊を組織しました
a new defensive force has been formed.
They will be called...
その名称は―
対亜人特選群です
The Anti-Ajin Special Force.
What’s this about?
（高橋(たかはし)）
んだよ これ
What about our civil rights?
市民権どころか―
Things are getting worse for Ajin!
ますます 立場
悪くなってんじゃねぇか！
Shit!
くそっ！
（ゲン）
た 対亜人特選群って―
They said “Anti-Ajin Special Force”...
そんなん相手にして 勝てんのかよ
Can we really beat an opponent like that?
What should we do, Tanaka-san?
（高橋）
どーすんだよ 田中(たなか)さん！？
If we mess this up,
all of us will end up at the research labs!
下手すりゃ
全員 研究所行きだぜ！
That’s why I said
（田中(たなか)）
だからって―
It’s too late. We can’t turn back.
今更 引き返すことなんて
出来ねぇよ
But-
（高橋）
でもな！
（田中）
引き返せる場所なんて―
There’s no place
left to turn back to!
もう ねぇんだ
今は…
Now...
佐藤(さとう)さんを信じるしかない
all we can do is trust Satou-san.
ん…
This is
（橋口）
これが新たに改良した―
the newly improved
レーザー目潰しです
blinding laser.
見てください
Please take a look.
It fires in 1.3 seconds,
0.3秒の照射で網膜を損傷させ
失明させる
and damages the retina, causing loss of vision.
（対亜隊長）
ほぉ…
This taser gun was also improved
to a strength of 2 million volts.
このテーザー･ガンも―
威力を200万ボルトまで
向上させました
Be they ajin or anything else,
亜人だろうが 何だろうが
一瞬で自由を奪う
this should instantly take away their freedom.
It’s wireless?
（対亜隊長）
ワイヤレスですか
Yes.
ええ 混戦になった際に
使い勝手がいいし―
In a free-for-all fight, it’s easy to use,
and we’ve made it able to rapid-fire.
連射も可能になりました
As for IBM countermeasures,
ＩＢＭ対策には
小型改良したインパルス放水銃
there’s the miniaturized impulse water cannon.
Oh, and
ああ それと―
スモーク･グレネードも
用意しておきました
I’ve also prepared smoke grenades.
And last is this.
最後に これです
ドイツの銃器メーカーと
共同開発した―
Jointly developed with a German small arms maker,
an airburst grenade launcher.
エアバースト･
グレネードランチャー
It hasn’t been used yet in actual combat,
実戦配備は まだですが―
but when we tested it here on-site,
当地でテストした際には―
エクスキューショナーと呼ばれ
随分 喜ばれました
the executioners were pretty happy with it.
死刑執行人ですか
Executioners?
By accurately detonating a high-explosive
projectile above a target,
標的の頭上で正確に りゅう弾を
さく裂させることによって―
we can render any cover ineffective.
遮蔽(しゃへい)物を無効化します
見てください
Please take a look.
効果のほどは
亜人の田中で実証済みですよ
As for whether it’s effective,
it’s been tested on the ajin Tanaka.
レーザー測距が
標的までの距離を測定し―
The laser range finder
measures the distance to the target,
and automatically transmits the detonation distance to the grenade.
エアバースト弾の信管に―
自動的に起爆位置を入力するのです
（曽我部(そかべ)）ほぉ
（コウマ）ほぉ…
It’s an outstanding weapon.
優れた武器です
Most importantly, you’re pleased with it.
気に入っていただけて何よりです
人数分 用意させましょう
I’ll have enough prepared for each
member of your forces.
Honestly...
（曽我部）
正直 ここまでとは
思いませんでしたよ
I didn’t expect this much.
In a few days,
（コウマ）
数日後には
佐藤も研究所行きだな
Satou will be headed to the research lab too.
（荷を積む音）
（佐藤(さとう)）
ああ そうだ 猫沢(ねこざわ)さん
Oh, that’s right.
Nekozawa-san...
来週あたりから しばらく
外国にでも出てたほうがいいよ
Next week or so, it’d be better to head
overseas for a bit.
（猫沢(ねこざわ)）
ああ？
Ah.
Things are getting kind of tough in this country.
この国
ちょっと大変なことになるから
佐藤さん
Satou-san,
あんた いったい
どこまでやるつもりなんですか？
exactly how far do you plan to take this?
（佐藤）
ん？
Hm?
この国を統治するまでだよ
Until I rule this country.
（猫沢）
え… ああ…
（永井圭(ながいけい)）
作戦決行は２日後
The plan will be carried out in two days.
（圭）
これが 正真正銘の
ラストチャンスです
This is genuinely our last chance.
The field is the headquarters of
Musashi Heavy Industries.
（圭）
フィールドは武蔵(むさし)重工本社ビル
（中野攻(なかのこう)）ひゅぅ
（真壁(まかべ)）フッ
Ooh!
Hm.
戸崎(とさき)さんの情報によれば―
According to Tosaki-san’s information,
取締役会が開かれるのは―
the board of director’s meeting will be held
最上階の会長室
in the president’s office on the top floor.
(screen- Headquarters of Musashi Heavy Industries)
The Anti-A’s will line the sides of the 24th floor.
（圭）
対亜が防衛線を張るのは24階部分
We’ll be located here.
僕たちが潜むのは ここ
21階の備品室が理想です
There seems to be a supply room
on the 21st floor.
（攻）
そんで佐藤たちが攻めてきたら
出てって戦うわけだな
Then when Satou and crew come to invade,
we’ll jump out and attack!
（圭）
そんなこと一言も書いてないだろ
There’s nothing at all written about that.
え？
Eh.
（下村泉(しもむらいずみ)）
まずは待機よ
First we’ll be on standby?
We can’t get involved in the fight between
Satou and the Anti-As.
（泉）
対亜と佐藤の戦いに―
巻き込まれるわけには
いかないでしょ
Oh, that’s right.
（攻）
あ そっか
対亜が落とされたら作戦開始です
Once the Anti-As are beaten,
our plan will begin.
僕と下村さんのチームが
接近戦を仕掛け―
Shimomura-san and my team
will prepare for a close-combat attack,
and we have Nakano as back-up.
中野がバックアップに回る
戸崎さんは通信支援をお願いします
Tosaki-san,
please handle communications.
Yes.
I already have the tools prepared.
（戸崎優(とさきゆう)）
ああ ツールは既に用意してある
これで残る問題は一つ
With this...
there’s only one problem left.
We need some way to get us into position...
僕たちが 戦いに介入出来る
措置を取ることですが…
The circumstances now are different
than with the minister.
今回は大臣の時とは状況が違う
I’ll think of a different way-
（泉）別の手段を考えたほうが…
（戸崎）余計な口を挟むな
Keep your mouth shut.
Come on, Tosaki-san!
（攻）
んだよ トザキさん
（攻）まだ怒ってんのかよ？
（戸崎）黙れ
Are you still mad?
Shut up.
We follow the plan,
当初の予定どおり 私が何とかする
I’ll figure something out.
Um...
あの 戸崎さん
Tosaki-san.
I’m still against it.
私は やはり反対です
下手をすれば 一生刑務所に…
If something goes wrong-
Shut up and drive.
黙って運転しろ
あ…
はい
Yes.
（曽我部）
ふんっ
自衛隊崩れに
元外国人傭(よう)兵部隊ですか
Considering the crumbling of the
Japan Self-Defense Force,
they were originally a foreign
mercenary squad?
They were passed down to me
and used by my predecessor.
前任者から引き継ぎ
使っていた連中だ
無論 大臣の承認は得たうえでな
Of course, with approval from the minister.
対亜が負けた場合の保険にしたいと
You want them as insurance in case
the Anti-Ajin forces lose?
そうだ
Yes.
They’re also used to dealing with ajin.
彼らなら
亜人の扱いにも慣れているし―
They’re pros when it comes to fighting.
戦闘に関しては完ぺきなプロ
（曽我部）
話になりませんね
It’s out of the question.
そもそも先輩は―
To begin with,
your expulsion from the Management
Committee has already been decided.
管理委員会からの除名が
決まってるんですよ
大臣殺害のごたごたで―
With the mess from the Minister’s assassination,
they just haven’t given the official orders.
正式な辞令が出ていないだけです
That’s why, if I get this final chance-
だから 最後のチャンスをくれと…
（携帯の着信音）
What is it?
（曽我部）
何だ？
Ah. Got it.
ああ 分かった
すぐに行く
I’ll be there soon.
As you can see, I’m busy with work.
見てのとおり 多忙な身でしてね
I’m sorry, but this is where I leave you.
申し訳ありませんが これで
The day this facility was attacked.
ここが襲撃を受けた あの日―
国防総省の連中を殺したんだ
I killed the man from the Department of Defense.
えっ？
オグラ博士の監禁が露見してな
The fact that they discovered Professor
Ogura's confinement-
Heh,
いや 参ったよ
that really got to me.
な 何を言ってるんですか 先輩
What are you saying?
ついに 頭がイカれたんですか？
Have you already lost your mind?
（戸崎）
かもな
Maybe.
しかし―
But if I leaked this incident,
もし 私が
この件をリークすれば―
私もお前も地獄行きだ
you and I would both go to hell.
な どうして僕まで…
Why me?
Ogura Ikuya is alive.
（レコーダー音声:曽我部）
オグラ･イクヤは生きている
あっ！
（レコーダー音声:大臣）
大したやつだ
He really is something.
アメリカ側の人間に手を出すとはな
To think he’d lay hands on an American.
（笑い声）
（大臣）
我々は この事実を知らない
We don’t know anything about this.
Got it? We know nothing.
いいか？　知らないんだ
（レコーダー音声:曽我部）
全ては戸崎先輩の身勝手な行動だと
Tosaki-senpai acted alone in all of
these selfish actions.
立派な組織犯罪だ
You’re a full-fledged criminal.
Shall we go to hell together?
仲良く地獄に行こうじゃないか
うっ…
くっ… 警備に加えるのは―
You want to add four people to security, is it?
４名でいいんですね
（戸崎）
５人だ
Five.
Shimomura-kun will move with us.
下村君も同行させる
（曽我部の舌打ち）
ああ それからな
Oh, and one more thing.
まだあるんですか？
There’s still something else?
（戸崎）
私の除名処分を取り下げておけ
Prevent my expulsion from the Committee.
（職員）
はい 警備部です
Yes, this is the security division.
（曽我部）
うっ… ぐっ…
（職員）
曽我部さん？
Sokabe-san?
（泉）
はっ…
うまくいったんですね
It went well, didn’t it?
はぁ…
買っておきました
I bought some for you.
あっ…
戸崎さん… あの…
Tosaki-san.
Um...
この前はすみませんで…
I’m sorry about earli-
あ…
君は君の仕事をしたまでだ
You did your job.
謝る必要はない
There’s no need to apologize.
What are you doing?
何してる？　さっさと出せ
Get the car moving.
Yes!
はい
（奥山(おくやま)）
なんとか間に合ったよ 秘密兵器
Somehow it’s finished in time.
The secret weapon.
はぁ…
（佐藤）
美しいな…
It’s beautiful.
（足音）
Hey, who are they?
（機動隊員１）
おい あれ…
（機動隊員２）
ああ 対亜だ
Ah, it’s the Anti-As.
（キャスター）
こちら
武蔵重工本社ビルから―
Reporting from 500 meters outside the headquarters
of Musashi Heavy Industries.
500メートルほど離れた地点から
お伝えしています
佐藤が襲撃を予告した時間まで―
Less than six hours remain before Satou's
planned attack on the facility.
６時間を切りました
According to those involved, the Anti-Ajin
Special Force has already been deployed,
関係者によると対亜人特選群が
既に配備され―
警備についているということです
and security are on the scene.
Additionally, all the staff of Musashi Heavy
Industries have been evacuated, so only
また 武蔵重工は
全社員を避難させており―
President Hashiguchi and a few officials remain in the building.
社内には橋口会長及び―
数名の役員のみが
残っているとのことです
Tonight, we bring the hammer down on the corporations who regard ajin
（佐藤）
今夜 我々は亜人を
ただの経済動物と見なし―
as mere animals for experimentation,
非道な実験を繰り返してきた
最後の企業に鉄槌(てっつい)を下す
and who have repeatedly carried
out unjust experiments.
That will be
それが
我々の真に望む未来への―
a big step towards
our hope for a new future.
大きな一歩となるはずだ
We depart at 1700 hours.
出発は1700(ひとななまるまる)時とする
Let’s give them a show today!
今日も派手にいこう
（黒木(くろき)）
ああ…
（真壁）
ふぅ…
（黒木）
お待たせっ
Sorry to keep you waiting.
（バッグを開ける音）
（圭）はっ…
（鈴村(すずむら)）ほい
（攻）はぁっ…
（インカム音声:泉）
配置につきました
We’ve arrived at our post.
Roger that.
了解だ
聞こえたな ＦＫ？
ゴースト対策は任せたぞ
However you think about it, I don’t
think we need insurance.
Ghost countermeasures are up to you.
（オグラ･イクヤ）
ふっ 天才に言うせりふじゃねぇな
That’s not what you say to a genius.
If signs appear,
give us instructions at once.
（モニター音声:戸崎）
兆候が出たら 即 指示をくれ
However you think about it, I don’t
think we need insurance.
どう考えても―
保険が必要になるとは
思えませんがね
ああ
Yes.
If the Anti-As can’t win,
対亜で勝てなけりゃ―
この国に 佐藤を止められる者は
おらんさ
there’s no one in this country
that can stop Satou.
（オペレーター）
衛星の設定 完了しました
How grand. You even brought satellites out?
豪儀だな
衛星まで持ち出したのか？
This is communications. Satellite setup complete.
With permission from the secretary of defense.
内閣官房から許可がおりましてね
（コウマ）
国も本気だ
The government’s taking this seriously too.
今日でこの馬鹿騒ぎを終わらせる
We can finally end this idiotic uproar today.
（ライトが点灯する音）
Five minutes remain.
（インカム音声:オペレーター）
５分切りました
衛星画像に異常ありません
Satellite footage shows all clear.
（インカム音声:機動隊員１）
ポイント･ツー 異常無し
Point 2. All clear.
Point 3. All clear.
（インカム音声:機動隊員２）
ポイント･スリー 異常無し
（インカム音声:機動隊員３）
ポイント･フォー 異常無し
Point 4. All clear.
How do they plan to arrive?
どう来る気だ？
ビル倒しは不可能ですよ
It won’t be possible to topple a building.
They can’t pull a stunt like that this time.
今回ばかりは
あんな芸当は出来ない
Our airborne defenses are flawless,
航空テロ対策も万全だし―
下水道も封鎖した
and the sewers have been closed.
This is
ここは難攻不落の要塞(ようさい)だ
an impregnable fortress.
（インカム音声:佐藤）
さあ 攻略開始といこうか
Well, shall we start our playthrough?
（木村(きむら)）
了解です
Roger that.
（エンジンをかける音）
（役員）
会長 まもなく
President.
Momentarily...
（橋口）
ん？　ああ…
Ah.
（橋口のため息）
始めましょう
Let’s get started.
（警官１）止まれ！　おい 止まれ！
（警官２）不審車両だ！
Stop! Oy! Stop! The road’s closed!
（警官たち）あっ おっ…
This is Point 2.
（インカム音声:機動隊員）
こちらポイント･ツー
封鎖線付近で不審車両が停車
A suspicious vehicle has stopped
at the roadblock!
From the front gate?!
正面からだと！？
飛んで火に入る… ですよ
Like a moth to a flame.
Don’t be afraid of damage.
Take them in!
被害を恐れるな！　確保しろ！
（機動隊員）
搭乗者に告ぐ　両手を挙げ
速やかに降車しなさい
Out of the vehicle!
Put both hands in the air.
Get down from the vehicle immediately!
（ドアが開く音）
（機動隊員）
降りろ！
Out!
We’ve got him!
（機動隊員）
確保！
あっけない
You weren’t good enough.
（機動隊員）
車両を確認しろ！
Check the back!
な 何だ？
What’s that?
Like I said,
だから 秘密兵器だよ
it’s a secret weapon.
ん？
（爆発音）
（戸崎）なっ…
（コウマ）あ…
（圭たち）
あ ああ…
あ…
Secure the backup!
The electricity!
（機動隊員１）
電源確保！　電源！
Switch it over!
（機動隊員２）
警戒しろ！
What’s going on?
（機動隊員３）
どうなってるんだ！
Oy!
（ざわめき）
（機動隊員４）落ちるぞ！
（ヘリコプターが降下する音）
It’s coming down!
（機動隊員）うわぁ…
（機動隊員）た 退避
W-Wait!
（爆発音）
（機動隊員たちの叫び声）
フフフッ
出番だよ 奥山君
It’s your turn, Okuyama-kun.
こ… こんな事が…
It- It's this bad already?
What’s going on?
Confirm the situation!
（機動隊員）どうなっているんだ！
（機動隊員）状況確認！
All electronic devices are down!
They can’t be started up!
（オペレーター）
全ての電子機器がダウン！
再起動も出来ません！
Power has been lost!
（オペレーター）
全電源が喪失しています
下村君 聞こえるか　下村君
Shimomura-kun?
Can you hear me?
Shit.
くそっ どうなってる！？
ＥＭＰだ
It’s an EMP.
は？
Huh?
やつら 爆薬発電機を作ったんだ
They made an electromagnetic pulse weapon.
With that, all electronics have burned out.
それで あらゆる電子機器の
回路を焼き切った
恐らくは 半径数百メートル以内の
電子機器は全て死ん…
It’s likely
that all electronics within a radius of
a few hundred meters are disabled.
（戸崎）
はっ！
（機動隊員）
何だ！？
What’s that?
（機動隊員）
撃て！
Fire!
派手にいこう
Let’s give them a show.
（爆発音）
（叫び声）
くっ く… くそーっ
Shit.
“作戦は奇をもって
よしとすべし”さ
I love it when a plan comes together.
はい　アンカー設置オーケー
リードロープ引っ張って
Alright.  Anchor setting OK.
Pull the lead rope.
了解
Roger!
（攻）
ど… どうなってんだよ！？
おい 永井！
What’s going on?
Nagai!
落ち着け 中野！
まずは目を慣らせ
Calm down, Nakano.
First, let your eyes adjust.
Tosaki-san.
戸崎さん　戸崎さん！
Tosaki-san!
It’s no good.
The connection’s dead.
駄目　インカムも死んでる
どーする
どーすりゃいい！？
What do we do?
What should we do?!
だから 落ち着いて 中野君
作戦どおり まずは待機…
Nakano-kun, calm down!
According to the plan, first we wait.
No...
いや
Let’s move.
動きましょう
Eh?
（泉）え？
（攻）な…
（モニター音声:高橋）
はぁっ はぁっ…
今度は電気屋かよっ
This time we’re electricians?
It’s called power line maintenance.
送電線架線工って言ってよ
（対亜隊員１）
エアバースト･
グレネードランチャー
Airburst grenade launcher.
Taser gun.
テーザーガン レーザー目潰し
全て使用不可能です
Laser blinding.
All impossible to use.
Communication devices are also dead.
（対亜隊員２）
通信機器も死んでます
This situation in itself is a chance.
この状況は逆にチャンスです
僕に考えがある
I have an idea.
（対亜隊長）
電子装備は全て放棄
通常装備でいく
Abandon all electronic devices.
Go with the usual equipment.
（窓が割れる音）
From here on...
（佐藤）
ここからは 火と刃物だけの
原始的な戦いだ
it’s a primitive fight with a single blade!
わくわくするだろ？
It really gets you going!
（攻）
ホントにうまくいくのかよ？
Will this really go well?
佐藤さんは有言実行の人だからな
Satou-san keeps to his word.
That will be his downfall.
それが命取りになる
Let’s start the plan.
作戦開始といきましょう
To be continued...
Mou akitakara koukan shiyou
Since I'm tired of it, let's exchange it
♪もう飽きたから交換しよう♪
Omae ga motteru futsuu no to
With the normal one that you are holding
♪お前が持ってる普通のと♪
Kira kira shiteru kami no kaado to
A shining paper card and
♪キラキラしてる神のカードと♪
Zara zara shiteru kami no kaado
A rough paper card
♪ザラザラしてる紙のカード♪
Kondo uchi ni kitara
Next time you come to my house
♪今度家に来たら♪
Zenbu miseteyaru yo dakara
I'll show you everything, so...
♪全部見せてやるよ♪
♪だから♪
Koutei no sumi ni futari, kaze ga fuite ima
At the edge of the schoolyard the wind blows...
♪校庭の隅に二人 風が吹いて♪
♪今なら言えるかな♪
nara ieru ka na?
can I say it now?
Dare nimo iwanai kotoba
Words never spoken to another person
♪誰にも言わない言葉♪
Yasashiku suru kara asobi ni kite yo
I'll be gentle so come and play often
♪「優しくするから
遊びに来てよ」♪
Nandemo ageru yo, ne
I'll give you anything, hey
♪「何でもあげるよ ねぇ」♪
Korekara zutto tomodachi de ite yo
Let's be friends forever
♪「これからずっと
友達でいてよ」♪
Preview
You’re the one who’s in the way.